The weather's better than this on
Saturday.
What are all these people doing here?
Oh, well, um... Seems like a lot of
fuss.
Even the simplest things need
preparation.
Do you want all four sides of the barn
painted or just the side that shows?
Huh? I don't know. What do you think,
Jasper?
Uh, well, just the side... Oh, fine and
dandy. I put some of my stuff in your
barn, Jasper. Is that all right? Uh, no.
There's a lot of fragile equipment in
there. The boys and I were real careful.
I'm sure you were, but, uh...
Aunt Olivia, Felicity and I have all the
flowers arranged.
Oh, we found this beautiful patch of
phenanthrope behind the Biggins boarding
house. They promised not to mow it down.
That's lovely, Sarah.
You just think, in only one week, you'll
be Mrs. Jasper Dale. I know.
Sarah.
Olivia. Hello, Felicity.
Hello there, Rebel. Hello.
Hello, Hetty.
Good timing. I need some advice.
Advice? How unusual.
Hetty, where do you think we should set
up the picnic after the ceremony?
Oh, far be it from me to give you any
advice about your wedding, Olivia.
Well, I swore from the start I wouldn't
interfere.
And I haven't. I appreciate that, Hetty,
but I... Did I object when he announced
you wouldn't need a wedding gown?
Did I rant and rave?
No, I did not.
I simply stopped by to see if you wanted
a ride home.
No, thank you.
There's a lot of work to be done around
here. We could use some help.
I'm sure you could.
Yeah.
What happened?
Oh, I suppose one of the boys couldn't
resist giving it a throw. Oh, Jasper,
sorry. No, no, no.
Just at least peep.
milling about.
You don't like it, do you? Like what?
Well, the idea of having the wedding
here.
All the people.
After, listen to me.
We don't have to go through with all of
this. A lot of you don't want to.
The only thing that matters to me is
that we get married.
There you go, Daniel.
I suppose things are going to be turned
upside down around here the next few
days. Oh, Alec, don't worry.
Everything's under control.
It's a shame Roger and Andrew can't be
here for the wedding, but they have
promised to send something special from
Brazil.
By the way, have you heard from your
great -aunt?
Oh, great -aunt Eliza wouldn't miss a
wedding for the world.
She's an old dear and you a moot.
Well, those aren't exactly the words
that jump to mind, but I have to...
promised to behave myself.
I don't know how you do it all.
You're a wonder.
Well, I'm just glad Libby decided to
keep the wedding simple.
It's not simple enough for Jasper,
Stace. I saw him in town today.
Looked like a man about to be dragged to
the gallows.
Poor dog.
Don't you have a home to go to?
Aunt Olivia?
Sarah! Did you hear that noise?
What noise?
What's that?
Well... Aunt Olivia!
You're going too low!
Sarah, please!
That's the most romantic thing I've ever
heard!
Olivia?
Sure you want to go through with it? Oh,
of course I do.
Olivia, King, as I live and breathe, you
are about to... Elope.
Elope? Isn't it romantic?
It is despicable.
How dare you even think of tarnishing
the King's name?
It was my idea!
Your idea?
It is obvious that neither of you is
capable of thinking in a rational
so...
Jasper Dale, home.
Sarah,
bed.
Olivia, inside.
From now on, I am in charge.
Eddie, listen to me. I do not need a
fancy wedding dress.
My blue or white suit will do just fine.
Since I've gone to the trouble of
arranging a proper church wedding,
have a proper wedding dress, though.
It won't do, Mom!
Nonsense, Cornelia.
Just do your corset up tighter.
The fine kettle of fish, Mrs. Lawson.
It's plain you took the wrong
measurements.
I couldn't...
have done that, Mrs. Bugle. I'm sure of
it.
Perhaps Cornelia has gained a little.
Stop that munching.
I don't want no excuses.
What are we going to do with the wedding
only days away?
Really, Mrs. Bugle?
This Saturday at four.
She's marrying that young Hiram
Sprocket.
Charming.
My sister Olivia is to be married on
Saturday at two.
Reverend Leonard's going to be a busy
man.
Now, see here, Mrs. Lawson, I either
want another dress or my money back.
Just look at that catalog.
Oh, oh.
That's a peach, a real peach. Isn't it
corny? That is the most expensive dress
in the book.
Potus Boy.
It's copied straight from a Paris
original. You know, the train is ten
long. It is very pretty, Aunt Olivia.
Come look.
Oh, no, it's far too grand for me.
Hattie, besides, look at the price.
Nothing is too good for my daughter.
We'll take it, too. Hattie!
Not to worry, Olivia.
No one at her wedding will ever be at
our wedding, so... Make sure you order
in the right size this time.
It will be here on time, of course,
Elvira.
Well, it is awfully short notice,
Hattie, but... Better be here before the
wedding, considering it was your mistake
that put us in this position.
I will do my very best, Teddy.
I mean, Mrs. Bugle.
Please do.
Oh, again, perhaps I should take some
measurements, Olivia.
That lot of good that seems to do.
Oh. Oh.
Perhaps we'll do that later.
I can... I can come back another time. I
see that you're busy.
Get on with it.
I bet you're sorry you didn't elope.
No, it's only right that Olivia should
have a proper wedding. No, I've said
all along.
But... Dang it! Sarah Stanley, if I
can't even get the proper words out in
normal conversation, how am I ever going
to get it through a marriage ceremony?
You'll be fine, Jasper. All you have to
say is, I do.
Yes, but... It was, uh...
Something else I'd very much like to
say.
What?
Well, in my head, I imagine...
I'd like to give a short speech.
A speech?
A toast.
To Olivia.
I'd like to stand up in front of
everyone and tell Olivia how I feel.
That's a lovely idea.
Yes, that's all it is. It's an idea.
And have you got the book of speeches?
I'll pick just the right one and I'll
coach you.
Jasper, you'll be fine. I'll help you.
Father, book the ballroom at the White
Sands Hotel for my reception.
Jasper!
Of course, there's an arm and a leg.
Kings don't hold with such crassness as
wedding receptions in public buildings.
Family celebrations have always been
held at the King Farm, you see.
Na -di -da, Miss King.
Come, Cornelia.
Have you spoken to Janet about this?
No, I have not.
Besides, Janet's opinion has nothing to
do with it.
Are you telling me the reception will be
here at my house?
Only if it rains. If it's sunny, we'll
have it outside.
Won't inconvenience you in the least.
Won't inconvenience me.
One thing, dear.
To prepare a picnic lunch, I was only
too glad to help out, but a reception
at King Farm for 50, with less than a
week to prepare.
I like your Janet to be so negative.
Hetty, King!
Have you lost your senses?
How dare you assume it would be fine
with me?
Have you any idea how much work goes
into organising an event like this?
She's here!
Oh, dear God!
Felicity, where's Daniel?
You know, if you were better organised,
Janet, you'd not find yourself in such a
constant tizzy about everything.
For heaven's sake, Alec, this rickety
old thing has got me black and blue all
over. I believe that you deliberately
look for every pothole to drive through
from that ghastly train station to here.
Oh, hello, Felicity.
You haven't grown at all.
Oh, there you are, Janet. I didn't lie,
sir. You look positively worn out.
Felix, give me a hand with this luggage,
will you?
Of course.
Let me take it to that dog. Get in here.
Get away from here.
Come on. Come on, boy.
Hey, I think I'll call you Digger.
Eliza, how nice to see you.
Oh, well, at least you'll be able to
appreciate all my plans for the wedding.
Alec, you've got to do something. Tell
her it's out of the question. Janet, I
in no mood. Let's just get this week
over with as quickly as possible.
Well, it's all very well for you to say.
I'm the one who has to do everything.
So you're going to have the reception at
your place.
Isn't that a splendid idea?
What?
That's what I was trying to tell you.
Alec, you know, you should spruce this
place up around here. Maybe this will
light a fire under you.
The baby's teetering.
Only one can see that from the long.
Isn't that better, Daniel?
Bravo.
Ah,
appropriate telephone speech.
What are you up to?
Oh, nothing.
Just something for the wedding. Oh, yes,
the wedding.
What's wrong, Aunt Olivia?
Oh, I don't know. I'm sure it'll all be
fine.
Jasper is happy now that it isn't at his
farm. It was really for him that I
wanted to, you know... Anyway, Hetty has
promised to keep it simple.
Oh, great Jehoshaphat.
It's four pages long, Sarah.
Hetty King, this...
It's supposed to be a family wedding.
Well, I don't even know some of these
people. Olivia, don't start.
It's taken me all day to compile that
guest list.
Oh, you have no idea how difficult it is
to do without slighting people right
and left.
Be thankful I did it for you.
Betty, it just isn't what we planned.
Jasper wants to keep it simple.
This is your wedding, Olivia, not
Jasper's. Remember that.
Now about the flowers.
There's nothing to look at locally,
that's for sure. I have to send to
Charlottetown, I suppose.
Eddie, Felicity and I are doing the
flowers.
Don't be silly, Sarah.
But the Queen Anne's place... Can stay
in Mrs. Biggin's backyard where it
belongs. I give up.
Obviously what I want doesn't matter.
I had hoped for a little cooperation.
There must be over 100 people on this
list.
122 not counting Olivia Jasper. Oh,
Alec! I don't know why you're calling
Janet. As far as I can see, he's never
here when you need him.
Besides, I'd be surprised if half those
people show at this late date.
Oh, Felicity!
Felicity! Get Daniel!
Felicity!
Mother, I can't do everything.
Sarah, you and Aunt Hetty can make
yourselves far more useful than just
around making lists.
Felicity!
Janet, I'd love a cup of tea, if you
don't mind.
I don't know why, but my bones are all
chill.
It's over 85 degrees outside, Annalisa.
Alec, that old plow behind the barn is
an eyesore.
You must get rid of it before the
wedding.
You don't feel the cold like I do.
Look, if she wants to plow moose, she's
got two arms.
Alec! Oh, you'll be old too one of these
days. You'll find out, Alec. Look at
this. This whole thing has gotten
totally out of hand.
Why don't you just tell Hattie?
Why me?
She's your sister.
It's your family wedding, Alec. I don't
see why Janet should bear the brunt,
especially with a six -month -old baby
into the bargain.
Why don't you just for once, Eliza, stay
out of this?
Don't you talk to my aunt like that.
It means no such thing, young lady. Just
do as you're told.
Come on.
There's no need to... I
never did get my
tea, did I?
She shows... She shows... But,
sir... Sir, I can't...
Talk with these things in my mouth. It
won't work. Just try it again.
No, all right.
Sea shells.
Sea shells by the seashore.
You see?
That was much better.
My elocution teacher swore by this
exercise.
Make sure to mark the knees of his
stutter.
Let's try the speech again. I think it's
a perfectly beautiful one, don't you?
It's a bit fervent. Just try it.
To my bride.
How can I describe the many ways that I
love thee?
My love.
My life.
My only reason for living.
I... Toast thing?
I love you.
Olivia's dress isn't here.
The wedding's tomorrow.
What are you going to do about it,
Alvara?
Does that mean that my daughter
Cornelia's dress isn't here either?
Oh, no.
Oh, hush, Cornelia. Please.
Ladies, I am doing my very best. Now, if
that dress isn't here tomorrow morning,
Elvira Lawson, I will throw a blue fit.
How sensible.
If Olivia's dress isn't here by 11 o
'clock tomorrow morning, the Kings will
take their business elsewhere from here
on in, Elvira. I promise you that they
will be here by 11 o 'clock tomorrow
morning if my husband has to drive to
Charlottetown to get them.
Goodness knows where to put Eliza.
Of course, she's not related to the
king's intruders.
There's not a ward who'll speak to her
except Janet. So I'll put her at the
table. Eddie, I don't want a head table.
There's no pleasing you, is there,
Olivia?
I just don't like the idea of sitting
apart.
I just don't like people staring at us.
I would like to have a simple picnic
buffet where we could mingle with our
guests. Mingle?
With a ten -foot train trailing along in
the dirt?
I didn't want a ten -foot train. And
with any luck at all, it won't arrive.
Well, there's gratitude for you.
Don't go to all this trouble bending
over backwards. Nobody asked you to,
for heaven's sake.
Stop shouting, both of you.
Don't you think I should have let you
run off into the night like a pair of
gypsies? I wanted you to have a wedding
you could be proud of.
You did not, Eddie King.
You wanted a wedding that you could be
proud of.
Well, whose wedding is it anyway, mine
or yours?
What a ridiculous question.
The only good thing about this whole
business is that I'll be able to move
from you and your constant interfering.
everything.
Just pride to be jitters, that's all.
She'll come to her senses.
There I...
I
toast thy innocence,
thy trust, and thy undying...
Devotion, my wife, my heaven sent, dove
of peace.
Olivia.
Jasper, I can't go through with this.
Eddie is... Why don't we just drive into
Charlottetown right now and get a
justice of the peace to marry us?
Olivia.
Jasper, you agreed before.
Only because I thought it would make you
happy.
you.
I'll be fine.
Do not worry about me.
Let's just go then.
I can't do that either.
Janet would never forgive me after
repairing all that food.
Oh, Jasper, I just don't know what to
do.
I tried so hard to keep everything
simple, and it's just completely out of
control. Tomorrow, it's just... One day
in the rest of our lives.
It's a very long day, most likely, but
it's just one.
We'll get through it.
You think so?
Yes.
I'm just so afraid that you'll hate it.
She even has us sitting at a head table.
No,
no, it will be fine.
A nice view.
Another night under the same roof with
that woman?
I don't think you can stay here.
It might not look as if... No, no, what
I mean is that... Jasper, I'm not going
back to Rose Cottage. You're not? No.
What about the cocaine farm? You could
stay there.
Oh, yes.
Janet wouldn't mind, would she?
She's sure to understand.
Where have you been?
I have been out moving that blasted
plow.
I just hope it makes your great Aunt
Eliza happy.
Children in bed?
Yes, they are.
No thanks to you.
Look, I can't be everywhere at once.
Oh, that's funny. I have to be.
Janet, why don't we stop this?
Janet! Could you be a dear and switch my
mattress with Felicity's? I can't abide
horsehair mattresses. My back, you know.
I tried to, Mother, but it's much too
heavy. Please, keep your voices down. I
just got the baby settled. Now, why
don't you two just switch beds?
Oh, I couldn't possibly.
Hers is much too close to the window.
With my arthritis...
What are you doing out so late?
I want to stay here.
You... What the...
Alec? Hello, Alec.
Oh, Olivia.
Dear, what's the matter?
Janet, it's Hetty.
I just can't stay there another minute.
She's being so horrible. Oh, there,
there, I know.
Now, look, both of you must stay here.
Come on, let's go upstairs.
Thank you.
Hetty has gone.
Yeah, well, tomorrow's the date.
Yeah, yeah, it certainly is.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You've got the ring, then?
Yes, I do.
Well, seeing as Felix is going to be the
ring bearer, maybe I'll drop by in the
morning and make sure it gets to the
church.
It's a good idea. Good idea.
I tend to forget things.
Especially, uh... Casper, you're not
nervous.
Me?
Some.
It's a big step.
One of the biggest steps you'll ever
take.
And I sincerely hope that Olivia and I
can be as happy as you and Janet.
Well, I'm sure you will be, even after
the honeymoon bliss is over.
Actually, it's the honeymoon part that
has me a little worried.
Oh, come on, man.
Olivia's a little high -strung. I know
she's bound to be a bit nervous, but...
I'm sure that Olivia will be fine.
Jasper, you're going to be fine, too.
Well, tomorrow's the day.
You better get home and get some sleep.
Yeah. That's a good idea.
See you in church.
Yeah. Right, Alec?
Crying out loud.
Shh. Oh, it's a baby.
What is she doing here?
Olivia's in her bed. Well, where am I
supposed to sleep?
Oh, now, look what you've done.
Look, every bed in this house is full. I
mean, it's a fine state of affairs when
a man can't find a place to sleep in his
own house.
Why don't you go and sleep in his
cottage? There's plenty of room there.
Ah, so you've moved in too, have you?
Why not? Everyone else has.
Eddie?
Hattie. Hattie.
Alec.
What are you doing here?
Well, no room at the end. I was hoping I
could bunk here.
Yes, of course you can.
Plenty of empty rooms.
It's all my own fault. I did everything
I swore I'd never do.
But I couldn't just stand there and
watch that marriage get off to such a
start.
Could I?
I want sister.
The only one I have left, and I've lost
her too.
You haven't lost her. She cares too much
about you.
Olivia's always been more like a
daughter to me, see, than a sister.
Now my life will be so empty.
It's not going to be the same.
But you can take it from a father who
knows you can have your hands full with
Sarah.
Everything's going to be fine, Hattie.
You come on over tomorrow.
It's one more person in that house. And
you help Olivia get ready.
And everybody's going to forget all of
this ever happened.
Now I'm going to get some sleep.
Thank you, Alec.
You can take Sarah's room.
Sarah.
Good night, Hattie.
best, dear Uncle Al. That a girl. I'll
turn the buggy around.
Sarah, it's here. That's wonderful.
Mrs. Bugle, I'll get yours, too.
It's here?
Well, hallelujah.
Here we are, Sarah. Tell Olivia to wear
it in good health. I will. Thank you so
much.
My Cornelia will be lucky to have good
health.
You've got new stomach powders, Mrs
Lawson.
Pure nerves, that's all. She can't keep
anything down.
Well, Olivia, you're going to be a
married woman before the day is out.
I hope it's not one of those cases of
marry in haste, repent at pleasure.
Janet, we have to be ready in an hour,
you know.
Oh, goodness, all that dress.
to play ball, go outside. You're only in
the way here.
And don't get dirty in those good
clothes.
Mother,
we don't have that much time. When are
you going to get dressed?
Suffocate. Stand still. Now, I'm going
to sew this ring into your pocket so you
don't lose it. No, I'm not going to lose
it. What do you think I am, a baby or
something? All right, all right.
Here.
Now, here's a hanky.
I don't need no dumb hanky.
We have work to do. Has your name on it?
Lord.
Must have mixed them up in
Charlottetown.
My
life.
My heaven sent.
My ring.
It's a symbol of... Get
up there!
Get down!
Lord love us. Size 8, not 18.
Give me the dress. No!
Go to old Peter.
We'll make it fit. We've got your dress.
Where is it? Polybius!
The wedding's first.
We'll leave Cornelia's dress in the
church. You can pick it up there.
Good day.
Ma, I'm going to be slick.
Jasper, don't blow your cell phone.
Oh.
Felix caught into it.
Take time, you.
Get down, darn you.
Felix,
hang me.
Come in here this moment.
Everything's fine. I can do it myself.
You look wonderful.
Teddy, what in blazes are you doing?
I'll tell that to the judge.
I, Jasper Thomas Dale, to take the
Olivia King to be my
lawful wife, according to God's holy
ordinance, to have
and to hold from this day forward, for
better and for worse, for richer, for
poorer, in sickness and in health, to
love
and to cherish.
Till death do us part.
Could we have the ring, please?
I give thee this ring as token and
pledge of the covenant made between us.
For as much as Olivia and Jasper have
consented together in holy wedlock, and
have declared the same before God, and
in the presence of these witnesses, I
pronounce you man and wife, in the name
of the Father, the Son, and the Holy
Ghost.
Look, Ma.
It's a gold ring.
Thank you so much.
Oh, Alec.
And so, as you start your journey into
married life, and believe me, it's an
adventurous one, we all want to wish you
the very best.
Here's to the happy couple.
I'd just like to take this opportunity
to say a few words about my new...
To Olivia.
To my bride.
How can I describe the many ways that I
love thee?
My...
My love, my... My life.
I think I'll say it in my own way.
To fall in love with Olivia, or even
more unbelievably,
to have her fall in love with me, is the
most astounding and... wonderful thing
that possibly could ever have happened
to me.
You are of most... You are the most
special person.
Now, I know how the King family rallied
together to
look after each other. For better or for
worse.
So I want to assure you all that I'm not
taking Olivia away from this fine,
solid family of hers, but rather that I
am honored to become
part of it.
I'd like to propose a toast to my
beautiful new bride, who means more to
me than...
Anything in the whole world.
To Olivia.
There you are.
Hello, Olivia.
Just making myself useful.
Eddie, I just... I just want you to know
that
the wedding was a wonderful idea.
It wouldn't have been right for me to
have been married without my family
surrounding me.
All the trouble we've been through.
She'll let you elope in the first place.
I'm going to miss you and Rose Cottage
so much.
Rose Cottage isn't going anywhere.
I'll always be there for you.
You'll be on your way now.
Your new husband's waiting for you.
Oh.
Oh, Olivia.
All those obvious shortcomings.
Jasper's come a long way with nothing
but you.
Oh, dear. No, it's true.
Congratulations, Jasper.
Oh, thank you.
Welcome to the family.
Thank you, Ellie.
Have a lovely trip, Aunt Olivia.
Thank you, Sarah.
A man is nothing but trouble, Olivia,
and all the uncertain things in this
world. Marriage is the most uncertain.
Well,
thank you for the advice, Aunt Eliza.